

Saugat Maharjan UI/UX & Graphic Designer | IT Engineer

J +977-9843687180

• Dhalko-17, Kathmandu

Personal Details

Profile

I'm a passionate UI/UX Designer with an Engineering Degree from Kathmandu, Nepal who loves graphic designing, I design and craft products and visual experiences from the user research to the high-fidelity design with more than 1 year of experience. My interest in design field sparked during pursuing the degree. Apart from my interest in technology, I have a passion for

traveling, drawing, playing video games, listening to music, learning new things, and taking on thrilling challenges. Additionally, I consider myself a food enthusiast who enjoys trying out different cuisines at all times.

Product Designer GlobalyHub, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

Employment

May 2022 - Nov 2022

Dec 2022 - Present

Associate UI/UX & Graphic Designer GlobalyHub, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

Design Intern

Dec 2021 - Apr 2022

Education

GlobalyHub, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology 2017 - 2022

CGPA - 3.07 Nepal College of Information Technology, Balkumari, Lalitpur

Higher Secondary Education 2015 - 2017

65.90% - First Division

Kathmandu Model College, Bagbazzar, Kathmandu

Maha Manjushree H.S School, Sitapaila, Kathamndu

School Leaving Certificate

80.38% - First Division with Distinction

Foundations of User Experience (UX)

2015

Jun 2022

Jul 2022

Aug 2022

Sep 2022

Oct 2022

Dec 2022

Dec 2021 - Apr 2022

2023

2023

2023

2023

2022

2022

2022

2022

2021

2019

Feb 2020

Feb 2014

Certificates

Credential ID: R5JKTCWJFARF **Start the UX Design Process:**

Prototypes

Concepts

Design

Empathize, Define and Ideate Credential ID: QUMJGP9MUCES

Credential ID: 9643NENPDM6J **Conduct UX Research and Test Early**

Credential ID: V3D9G84SHKTG

Create High-Fidelity Designs and

Responsive Web Design in Adobe XD

responsive implementing Design System

· Deployed website using Webflow

Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity

Prototypes in Figma Credential ID: YRNQESVB83D7

Credential ID: JLCLUVGQ8CB7

Real-Time Projects

GlobalyHub Website Designed the GlobalyHub website from scratch to fully

OHC Guide

Refactored design following Auto-Layout • Extending and Managing Product Features, Creating User

Design Intern

GlobalyHub, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

Professional Projects

NepaWatch - Figma

Travel App - Figma

File Transfer App

Ghumfir

Blog Site

Cab Booking

<u>Ghumfir - Figma</u>

Blogpost Article - Figma

Academic Projects

Major Project (8th semester)

Minor Project (6th semester)

First Project (4th semester)

Library Management System using

Second Position on Men's Cricket

First position in Inter-house Football

Annual sports week held by school.

Achievements

an UI/UX Designer

Ghumfir - Figma

Github - Code

Python and Django

Ghumfir: Companion Finder as

File Transfer App - Figma

UI Travel Kit

NepaWatch - Website for Smartwatch

Interface and User Experience Website Revamp [Design, Copywriter, Development (HTML, CSS, JS]

Implemented Design System, Components & Variants,

- Internships

www.saugatmaharjan.com

.np Linkedin

Website

saugatmaharjan-471a86225/ Nationality

https://www.linkedin.com/in/

Place of Birth

Nepali

Kathmandu, Nepal

Date of Birth

April 9, 1999 Gender

Male

Adobe XD

Skills

Figma

Illustrator

Webflow

Photoshop

JS

HTML/CSS

Qualities

Active Person, Problem-

Solving, Persevering, Reliable, Flexible.

Compatible and Friendly,

Teamwork and

SCSS/Tailwind/ Bootstrap

Collaborations.

- Analytical Thinking. Strong ability to balance multiple priorities with excellent time
- Excellent oral and written communication and

to communicate confidently.

presentation skills, ability

management skills.

Ability to lead and work

well in teams.

Languages Nepali

Flower Catalogue App Flower Catalogue App for Trendy Florist - Figma

Gamified Healthy Eating App

Gamified Healthy Eating App - Figma

2022 **Employee Task Management** Employee Task Management - Figma

Cab Booking - Figma

2020 **Smart Travel Planning Application** using Flutter with Dart

Extracurricular Activities

Held on occassion od Annual Sports Day by NCIT college.

Received cash prize for being topper in IT department in NCIT college in 5th semester.

Kathmandu Model College.

Facebook - Saugat Maharjan | Facebook

Instagram - (@s.a_u.g.a.t_7)

college in 8th semester.

 Awarded by Kilagha Twa: for securing Distinction position among SLC candidates on 5th December 2015.

Received cash prize for being topper in IT department in NCIT

 Received Scholarship to study Intermediate (+2 Science) program for securing good marks in entrance exam at

- Social Medias
- Linkedin Saugat Maharjan | Linkedin

Declaration

I consent to the processing of my personal data for purpose of recruitment for the position to which I am applying. I hereby declare that all the mentioned particulars are true about myself and take all the responsibilities for their correctness.

English

Newari

Hindi

Travelling Drawing Video Games

■ Football, Futsal

Music, Movies

History

Exploring and Learning

Hobbies